

# Noor ul Islam Huzaifa

• Address: H.No R-102, Gulistan e malir, Karachi, Sindh, 75210, Karachi, Pakistan

Email address: contact.noorhuzaifa@gmail.com Email address: huzaifa@mastrry.com

**Phone number:** (+92) 3132760198 **Phone number:** (+92) 3079355816

**⚠ Website:** <u>mastrry.com</u> **⚠ Whatsapp Messenger:** +923132760198

LinkedIn: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/noor-ul-islam-huzaifa-67505a201/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/noor-ul-islam-huzaifa-67505a201/</a>

Twitter: <a href="https://twitter.com/Diple\_me">https://twitter.com/Diple\_me</a>

**Gender:** Male **Date of birth:** 11 Dec 2002 **Nationality:** Pakistani

#### **ABOUT ME** -

Innovative, Good Conversationalist and Task-Driven Professional with 2+ years of Development Experience aquired from completing various projects singlehandedly and by being a core contributor in a team. I have experience in designing, developing, testing and debugging frontend dashboard and websites. I am keen on learning backend design and will to love to advance in the field of backend development.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE** -

[1 Jun 2021 - Current] React Js Freelancer

Fiverr.com

**City:** Faisalabad **Country:** Pakistan

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Bug Fixing
- Product Landing Page Developement
- $\,{}^{\circ}\,$  Design Implementation from Figma to React js
- Backend API Integration with the frontend
- Finding solutions to optimize app performance

### [ 1 Aug 2021 - 12 Aug 2022 ] MERN Stack Intern (Frontend Oriented)

## **EPTeck**

**City:** Faisalabad **Country:** Pakistan

Main activities and responsibilities:

- Product Landing Page Website
- A responsive and modern website landing page development.
- Used React Js as the Primary Driver and Tailwind Css as the design Language.
- ∘ Legacy React Js Code Refactoring & Optimization
- I was responsible for the maintenance of old legacy code of a frontend dashboard.
- Optimized and Refactored the legacy frontend dashboard and improved the initial web page load from 4.7 seconds to 920 ms.
- Analytical Dashboard Design and Development
- $\,^\circ\,$  Designed the UI of the dashboard in Figma & Adobe Illustrator
- Developed a Frontend Dashboard with React Js which was used to visualize a bunch of metrics and data.
- API Testing with Swager and Integeration with 55+ APIs and 7+ Pages from a backend prewritten in java spring-boot.
- Backend Cloud Service
- Shell Scripting through Node Js
- Implemented RPA through Node Js for automatic backend server creation through the Parse Platform Server.
- Integration with many MongoDB databases.
- Designed and Developed a MongoDB Instance to store auth data and credentials of other active MongoDB Instances.

### **EDUCATION AND TRAIN-**

ING

## [ 22 Oct 2020 - Current ] Bachelors Of Computer Science

### Riphah International University Faisalabad

Address: Adjacent Fish Farm, Satayana Rd, Faisalabad, Punjab, 44000, Faisalabad, Pakistan

# [ 13 Oct 2018 – 3 Mar 2019 ] **Programming Fundamentals**

**NED University Karachi** https://www.neduet.edu.pk/

Address: Service Rd, NED University Of Engineering & Technology, Karachi, 75270, Karachi, Pakistan

## [ 12 Apr 2019 - 9 Sep 2019 ] **Android App Development**

**NED University Karachi** <a href="https://www.neduet.edu.pk/">https://www.neduet.edu.pk/</a>

Address: Service Rd, NED University Of Engineering & Technology, Karachi, 75270, Karachi, Pakistan

## **DIGITAL SKILLS**

## **My Digital Skills**

## **Main Skills**

Tailwind CSS | HTML5/CSS, Javascript | MySQL | Bootstrap | React Js | Node Js | MongoDB | Express Js

### **Relevant Skills**

SwaggerOpenAPI | Unit Testing | Typescript - basics | Postman | GIT & Github | API Testing

### LANGUAGE SKILLS

Mother tongue(s): Urdu

Other language(s):

**English** 

LISTENING C2 READING C2 WRITING B2

**SPOKEN PRODUCTION B2 SPOKEN INTERACTION B2**